Wh-What's the matter, Master Rio?
Huh?
W-Wait! It's not like that!
It's a misunderstanding! This is—
How can this be?
Onii-chan?! Who is that?
Wh-What is going on here?
I-I'm telling you,
this is a misunderstanding!
A misunderstanding?!
Th-This is just—
That's right! It's a misunderstanding!
Everyone, calm down!
Miss Sara, thank you so much.
M-Master Rio is simply sleeping
with a naked woman, that's all!
And we've simply seen something
we weren't meant to see!
We're the ones actually at fault here!
Miss Sara, please calm down!
I-I'm so very sorry!
Who is she? Who? Who?
Th-That's right!
Who are you?
I don't understand what's
going on here at all!
Do you think you could explain things to me?
A spirit.
What?
I am the spirit who formed
a covenant with you, Haruto.
Seirei Gensouki
A Spirit's Awakening
I see. So you're the bonded
spirit Lady Dryas spoke of.
It's very weak, but I sense the
presence of a spirit from within you.
So... how did you and I form a covenant?
I don't know.
When I was still small, it was you who
showed me how to use spirit arts, wasn't it?
We don't have time right now.
I will teach you about od,
and how to use your magic power.
Learn it by remembering this feeling.
I don't know.
Then why have you suddenly appeared here?
Up until now, you've been
asleep inside me, right?
I don't know.
Is this what happens when a
bonded spirit first appears?
W-Well...
You see, the spirits we're bonded with
aren't person-shaped, so we don't really know.
I see.
What's your name?
I don't know my name, either.
I want a name.
I am by your side, Haruto.
That's why I want a name.
You mean I should give you a name?
Is that wrong?
It's not wrong, but why me?
Because I exist for you, Haruto.
Is that so?
U-Um, Master Rio?
This whole time, she's been
calling you Haruto...
I'll explain later.
About my name...
I know it. Rio.
I know everything about you, Haruto.
You can do things like this, too?
I can speak this way if
it's with you, Haruto.
I see. When you say you know everything,
do you mean everything about Amakawa Haruto?
Do you mean the Haruto that you
were before you became this Haruto?
It seems you do know everything.
Don't worry. I won't tell the others.
Would it be better if I called you Rio?
No, you can call me by either name.
Onii-chan! What's wrong?
N-Nothing!
About your name... Are you sure you're
all right with me giving you one?
I want a name you give me, Haruto.
All right. Will you give me a little time?
Yes.
Still, this all happened so
quickly that I'm not sure what to do.
What if you asked the Eldest
and Lady Dryas for advice?
Ask Lady Dryas?
That's a good idea!
Lady Dryas is a person-shaped spirit, too,
so she may have some counsel for you.
That's true.
Will you come with me?
Yes.
O-Oh, but before that, your clothes—
Will this clothing do?
Those clothes...
I wove them from od and mana.
Oh, so that light was from
a spirit art technique.
They're so pretty!
Aishia.
Your name... What do you think of "Aishia"?
Aishia?
In the ancient language of our village,
it can mean "warm springtime"
or "beautiful springtime."
Spring?
No, it's... When I looked at you,
the image of spring just seemed to fit.
Yes! I like it!
I like Aishia!
A warm spring. Spring,
like the "haru" in Haruto!
If you like it, then...
Nice to meet you, Aishia! Oh, should
I treat you like an older sister?
That would be disrespectful of you.
Welcome, Lady Aishia.
Welcome!
This person is Sir Rio's bonded spirit?
So she's finally awakened.
Yes, this morning.
We've heard from Sara and the others.
Seems there was quite a commotion.
It was all so sudden...
But I wonder why she has lost her memories.
Her covenant with me is—
Lady Dryas?
I felt a powerful spirit appear
within the village's barrier.
You must be Rio's bonded spirit.
I'm Dryas.
I'm Aishia. It's nice to meet you, Dryas.
It seems she's a spirit
that I don't know, either.
Generally, it is appropriate
for person-shaped spirits
to keep their memories from
before their elevation.
Aishia, you don't remember what
kind of spirit you were, do you?
I am Haruto's bonded spirit.
Haruto?
Yes. There's a bit of a
situation regarding that.
The truth is that in the Strahl region,
I am wanted by the authorities.
When I'm in Strahl, I call myself Haruto.
As it is you, Sir Rio, I am sure the
circumstances must have been extreme.
Let us set aside that
discussion for the moment.
Thank you very much.
For now, it would be good if we could
identify what kind of spirit she is, but...
Aishia, what element are you best at?
All of them.
By all of them, you mean...
That's surprising.
So... you mean that you're proficient
with spirit arts of every element?
I think so.
I'll really be fighting Aishia?
I've never heard of an all-around-type
person-shaped spirit.
I think an understanding of
how much power Aishia has
is something you need to know, too, Rio.
I understand.
When this stone hits the ground,
our battle will commence.
Are you ready?
Yes.
She's fast!
Amazing!
Her movement... Has she traced
and copied my techniques?
I think that's enough close combat.
This is a really intense battle.
She disappeared?
She changed to spirit form.
That's the same amount of power as the
spirit arts that defeated the black wyvern!
End of match!
I'm so very sorry! I got carried away!
If we continue this any longer, I think
something dire might happen to the village.
When Lady Aishia said she was capable in
every element, it seems she spoke the truth.
Yes.
And I think the strength we saw her use is
probably only a fraction of what she has.
Truly amazing.
But as she is now,
she's still unsafe as a spirit.
Aishia, starting now, I will impart
knowledge about spirits to you.
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
Lady Aishia, we, the People of the Spirits,
welcome you with all our hearts.
Thank you.
The only ones who can take
person-shaped forms as we can
are spirits of at least
the second-highest level.
You've made quite an impressive house.
Yes. I made a bath, too.
A bath, too?
It's a stone-lined bath.
As long as you use spirit arts
to set a foundation for it,
you can set it up wherever you want.
Master Dominic, I am truly grateful to you.
Cut that out. You act like we're strangers.
I was hoping to pay my respects
to the Eldest tonight.
Huh? Respects?
You've completed a house I can carry with me.
I was thinking it's about
time for me to depart.
Wh-When will you be leaving?
The day after tomorrow.
What?
I see.
Well, then, I'll talk to Syldora and Ursula.
Let's meet at the council hall.
Thank you.
W-Well, then!
Time to get ready for the evening meal!
Will you all help me?
Yes! I'll make Onii-chan's
favorite foods for him!
Thank you!
It's quite a sudden departure, isn't it?
What?
Yes, I'm sorry.
I'd decided to go whenever
the house was ready.
We're fine. It's Latifa...
Please spend a little
time talking with Latifa.
I've been thoughtless.
Since Aishia awakened, I've been too
focused on my spirit arts training.
I haven't been talking with Latifa as much.
Onii-chan...
I was thinking I'd like to wash
your back for you, Onii-chan.
Can I?
No, you can't! That's just...
Don't worry. I'm wearing a
bath towel and everything.
That's not the problem!
Onii-chan, you're leaving the
village the day after tomorrow.
It's just today. That's fine, isn't it?
No! Go put on your clothes!
Then I'm going to get in the bath
just like this! Is that better?
All right! You can wash my back!
Really?
J-Just today, understand?
Your back really is broad, Onii-chan.
Is it?
Yeah!
I wonder if it'll be even
broader the next time we meet.
I wonder, too.
Onii-chan, I told you before that
I used to be Japanese, right?
Yes.
My name back then was Endo Suzune.
What's this all of a sudden?
Big Sis Aishia calls you Haruto, right?
You said it was your alias
in the Strahl region,
but I just thought, maybe...
Amakawa Haruto.
That's my name from before
I reincarnated, when I lived in Japan.
I thought that must be it!
What?
I used to take the bus to school, you see.
There was someone I wished was my big brother
who took the same bus as me every day.
But the bus got into an accident.
Then... Latifa, could it be that
you were in that bus accident, too?
I see.
It's just like I thought.
You're a wonderful big brother!
I'm a terrible big brother
for not being with you more.
I'm sorry.
You're going to make sure to come home
to the village this time too, right?
If you're waiting for me, I'll come back.
No! You have to come back, no matter what!
I guess I have to make sure
to come home, then.
Yeah!
Oh, is there anywhere
that needs more rinsing?
This isn't a hair salon.
There's something I have
to do in the Strahl region.
It's all okay. You don't
have to tell me a thing!
Sir Rio, please take this.
It seems to have some kind of
magical formula sealed inside it.
It's a teleportation crystal.
It's a magic item that allows the user
to teleport to designated coordinates.
That one has been set to this village.
Using it will allow you to
come back here quite easily.
But it only works in one direction,
so it can't take you back
to where you came from.
A spirit stone of this caliber
must be very precious.
You are our sworn friend.
To let a sworn friend set out
on a journey empty-handed
would sully the name of
the People of the Spirits!
Oh, right.
You didn't forget the stone
house we built, did you?
No, I have it in the space-time cache.
Take this with you, too.
It will allow you to change the
color of your hair at will.
My hair?
If you are a wanted man in Strahl,
then I am sure it will prove useful.
Thank you very much.
Aishia, don't forget what I've taught you.
I won't.
Please look after my little sister.
We will! Leave her to us!
Honestly! I'm not a child!
Have a safe trip.
Thanks. I will.
There's something I have to do in Strahl,
but before that, there's someone I want to see.
Celia?
That's right. You know everything.
After that first letter, I haven't been
able to communicate with her, but...
So this is where you've been.
Lord Charles...
How formal. Won't you
call me "darling," Celia?
I-I couldn't. I'm too shy
to do anything like that.
That feminine modesty of
yours is truly splendid.
I look forward to seeing
how you will change in time.
Lord Charles!
If you would come with me, my lord.
Dear, dear...
In these times, with our
kingdom in such chaos,
while the great Houses do
bear great responsibility,
being so busy is quite the inconvenience.
If you aren't there, Lord Charles,
everyone around will grow anxious.
Please don't spare a thought for me and go.
Then, we'll meet again soon.
Yes, my lord.
Rio...
Beltrant, Royal Capital of the Beltrum Kingdom
Year 1000 of the Holy Era, Spring
Is something wrong?
No. I was just thinking,
it seems really crowded.
It was bustling before, too, of course.
Shall we try asking over there?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you.
Thanks for your patronage.
There are a lot of people passing by here.
Oh, it's because tomorrow there's
going to be a noble's wedding parade.
Apparently, lots of people have come
from outside the royal capital.
Nobles? From which House?
Duke Arbor's House.
I see. One of the great noble Houses.
I'm going to the Academy next.
Aishia, you can rest if you'd rather.
I'm fine. I'll go, too.
As I can take spirit form,
I'm sure I'll be useful.
Then, I suppose I'll be counting
on you, with my thanks.
Yes.
Before, this was easy to unlock, but...
I suppose I should have just
asked you in the first place.
Stay safe... until you return, all right?
She's not here?
This is...
Did she change research rooms?
She wouldn't have quit
the Academy, would she?
What will you do?
It's a bit of a risk,
but if there are researchers
in any of the other rooms,
we can use illusions and ask them.
All right. Leave it to me.
Is someone there?
I have some business with
Celia Claire. Where is she?
Oh, she's in the royal palace.
The royal palace?
Ahead of the wedding ceremony.
I'm sure they're wary of Duke Huguenot's
faction making a move.
Wedding? Whose?
Celia's, of course.
Professor Celia is getting married?
Who is she marrying?
Lord Charles of the House of Duke Arbor.
Charles...
She's marrying Charles Arbor?
Next Time
Silver Bride
"Silver Bride."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
I know
everything
about
you,
Haruto.
By Minazuki Futago
Every-
thing?
Your
schedule
yester-
day.
Your
schedule
last week.
Your
schedule
tomorrow.
That's
pretty
useful.
I'll ask her when I'm not
sure about my schedule